Carlos Emanuel Klema

Full Stack Developer

Villa Carlos Paz- Córdoba, Argentina (+54) 9 3541695544 carlosklema@hotmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub

I am a passionate Full Stack Developer with skills for teamwork, leadership, and teaching. My experience includes 1 year of study and practice related to web design, servers, and databases, supported by knowledge in agile methodologies, GIT, and the integration of libraries and frameworks. I have developed both in Front End and Back End, using technologies such as JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, and socket.io. My soft skills stand out for effective communication, problem-solving, calmness, and adaptability. My English proficiency is at a C1 level, and my Portuguese proficiency is conversational.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer - Countries Project
 Individual Proyect. Henry Bootcamp

oct. 2023 - oct. 2023

Project Description: Informational website containing basic data about all countries in the world.

Features: Display a list of countries along with their basic information, search for countries through combined filters or by name, access detailed information and additional details for each country, and register as a user.

Front: Javascript, React, Redux, CSS

Back: Node.js, Express,

Base de datos: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

Repo: CountriesProyect

Full Stack Web Developer - LoCanjeamos
 Proyecto Final. Henry Bootcamp

oct. 2023 - nov. 2023

Project Description: Single Page Application (SPA), in Progressive Web App (PWA) format, facilitating direct exchange of items between users. This promotes circular economy and sustainability by enabling people to swap goods they no longer need, encouraging reuse, waste reduction, and creating a collaborative space for more mindful resource sharing.

Features: User registration with the option to log in with a Google account, purchase a subscription as a premium user, search for products using filters, publish products, live chat functionality, rate other users, switch between light and dark mode, admin control panel, event notifications via email, and subscription to push notifications.

Front: JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS

Back: Node.js, Express,

Database:: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

Individual Contributions: Project structuring, modularization, and initial configuration, live messaging with

socket.io, matchmaking system.

Repo: Lo-Canjeamos

Web-site: locanjeamos.com.ar

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer – TiendasLocales
 FreeLance Job.

dec. 2023 - jan. 2024

Project Description: Single Page Application (SPA), in Progressive Web App (PWA) format. In my role as a Full Stack Developer, I participated in the development of an innovative web platform designed to connect and empower local businesses in a city of 15,000 inhabitants. This project aimed to create a virtual space that fostered seamless interaction between residents and local merchants, emulating the experience of an online shopping platform dedicated to the community.

Contribution: I implemented a robust Redux system for efficient Backend-Frontend communication and streamlined CRUD operations for essential database models. I designed intuitive interfaces, ensuring coherent information distribution, and integrated a notification system for enhanced user engagement. Additionally, I developed interactive forms with robust validations, playing a crucial role in user processes.

Front: JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS

Back: Node.js, Express,

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

Repo: TiendasLocales

Web-site: https://www.tiendaslocales.com.ar/#/

Full Stack Teaching Assistant
 Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

sep. 2023 - nov. 2023.

- Coordinating a group of students to facilitate integration into the study team.
- Assisting in the resolution of exercises and promoting group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Proposing ideas for the improvement of Bootcamp processes.

I have 5 years of work experience in the hospitality sector, specifically in positions such as assistant waiter, waiter, maintenance, receptionist, head waiter, restaurant manager, cashier, and baker.

TECNOLOGIES:

Languages: Javascript - Java - CSS

Frameworks: React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Socket.io,

Database: PostgreSQL, Sequelize

tools: Git, VSC, Discord, Slack, pgAdmin, GitHub

Agile: Scrum.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 800 horas de cursado teórico-práctico. 2023.
- Bachiller en Ciencias Naturales. Instituto Parroquial Bernardo D'Elia. 2012 2018.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish
- C1 level of English
- Basic proficiency in Portuguese

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Agile learnerProblem solver
- Strong communication skillsLeadership